Kahler, Erich von; Papers ger048
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Manuscripts by Kahler, 1907-1970; 3
  - "Fortdauer des Mythos" T., Undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - "Fortdauer des Mythos" - German Mss., Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - The Germans. Original Introduction., 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - The Germans. "Introduction" A., 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - The Germans. "Chapter One: The Abnormality of Germany." First Version, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - "Chapter Two: The Confrontation. 1. The Roman Empire", 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - The Germans. "Ch.2. P.2. Germanic Tribes." First Version, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - The Germans. "Chapter III: The Early Frankish Kingdom." Lecture Notes, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - The Germans. "Chapter IV: Charlemagne" Lecture notes. A., 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - The Germans. "Chapter V: The Formation of the Feudal System", 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - The Germans. "Chapter VI: The Development of the French Nation", 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - The Germans. "Chapter VII: Imperium et Sacerdotium" Lecture Notes, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - The Germans. "Chapter VIII: The Incomplete Feudalism in Germany and its Disintegration", 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - The Germans. "Chapter IX: The Great Transformation: Territorial States", 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - The Germans. "Chapter 10: The Territorial States and the 'Estates'.", 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - The Germans. "Chapter 11: The Peculiar Origin of the German Cities", 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - The Germans. "Chapter Twelve: The Rise of the German City", 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - The Germans. "Chapter Thirteen: The Innovation of the German Inland cities", 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - The Germans. Correspondence and other materials concemingthe posthumous publication of the Germans, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - "Germany and the Western World" A., Undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - "Germany and the Western World" -Mss., Undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Geschicte des Menschen - Early Mss. and notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Geschicte der Menschen "Fruche Entwurfe" -Mss. Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Geschicte der Menschen - Mss., Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Doctor of Letters - Honorary Degree - Princeton University, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Geschichte Des Menschen und des Menschencharakters - Notes, Quotations, Clipping, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Geschichte des Menschen und des Menschencharakters - "Die drei Werdenformen des Menschen", 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Geschichte des Menschen und des Menschencharakter - "Die Formen menschlicher Germein schaft", 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Geschichte Des Menschen und des Menschencharakters - "Geistige Einheit", 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Geschichte Des Menschen und des Menschencharakters - "Gestalt des Lebendigen", 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Geschichte Des Menschen und des Menschencharakters - notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Goethe Lecture" - Mss., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Die Griechische Denktat" - "Einleitung: Werden und sein", 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "Die Griechische Denktat" - "Der Gang Des Griechischen Denkens", 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Die Griechische Denktat" - Aristoteles" notes, 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "Die Griechische Denktat" - "Platon Notizen", 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Die Griechische Denktat" - "Stoa, Neoplationism und Christentum" - Notes, 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "Grosse und Tragik Stefan Georges" Mss. Lecture, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "Hat die Gechichte einen sirin?", 1964 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - "Herkunft und Sinn Des Modernen Romans" - Mss., Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "A History of the German Character" - Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "Hohe des Lebens" - Photocopy of poem, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - "Holderlin inder Deutschen Dichtung" - Mss., Undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - "The Hydrogen Bomb (and Professor Urey) - Mss., 1950 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "In Reply to Dr. Carl Meyer's 'Anti Judaism Reconsidered" - Mss., Undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - The Inward Turn of the Narrative Introduction - "On Consciousness", Undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - "The Inward Turn of the Narrative" - Proofs, Undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Israel Unter den Volkern - Introduction, Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Israel Unter den Volkern - "Der Judische Charakter" - notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Israel Unter den Volkern - Untitled Mss., Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Israel Unter den Volkern - Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - J.H. Untitled Discussion of Kahlers's Israel Unter den Volkern, Undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - "Jews Among the Nations" - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - "The Jews and the Germans" - Lecture Mss., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - "Das Kunstwerk und die Geschichte Mss., Undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - "Lebensverwandlung des burger - Lichen wesens" - Mss., Undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - "Lebensverwandlung des burger - Lichen wesen" - notes, cl., Undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Men the Measure - Diagrams and Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Men the Measure - "A History of the Human Quality Introductory Remarks", Undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Men the Measure - Introduction: "The Basic Problem of our Time" Mss., Undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Men the Measure - Introduction, Undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Men the Measure - "Physical Preliminaries", Undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Men the Measure - "Kingdom of Man" - Mss., Undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Men the Measure - "Der Primitive Mensch", Undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Men the Measure - "Partizipation. Der Primitive Mensch." - Mss., Undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Men the Measure - "Primitive Peoples" - Lecture Mss., Undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Men the Measure - "Oriental Kingdoms" - Lecture Mss., Undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Men the Measure - "The Greeks" - Lecture Mss., Undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Men the Measure - "Democracy" - Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Men the Measure - "Anmerkungen", Undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Men the Measure - Correspondence, 1943-1944; 1951 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Men the Measure - Miscellaneous notes, Mss. P., Undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - The Meaning of History - Mss., 1946 March (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - The Meaning of History - Notes, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - The Meaning of History - Materials, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - The Meaning of History - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Memorandum - Seminar on Humanistic Studies, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Seminar in the Humanistic Studies - Correspondence, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Seminar in the Humanistic Studies - Mimeo Text: Notes Toward a Structural Interpretation of a Crisis, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Menschheitsidee und Kulturgestaltung in Vergangenheit und Zukunft "Einleitung, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Menschheitsidee und Kulturgestaltung in Vergangenheit und Zukunft "Die Entstehung des menschlichen Indiviuums", Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Menschheitsidee und Kulturgestaltung in Vergangenheit und Zukunft "Weltreligion, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Menschheitsidee und Kulturgestaltung in Vergangenheit und Zukunft "Die Enstehung des Menschlichen Kollektivs", Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Menschheitsidee und Kulturgestaltung in Vergangenheit und Zukunft "Die Vorherrschaft der Wirtschaft und Technik", Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Menschheitsidee und Kulturgestaltung in Vergangenheit und Zukunft "Das Vorspiel Der Gropen Krise", Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Menschheitsidee und Kulturgestaltung in Vergangenheit und Zukunft Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Molif and Motive - The Origins of Thomas Mann's 'Doctor Faustus'" - Lecture Notes, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "Oesterreich" Mss., Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Oesterreich, Habsburgs - Notes Mss., Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Out of the Labyrinth - Mss. Notes, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "The Prophecy of George" - Mss., Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - "Die Prosa des Expressionismus" Mss., Undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - "Die Prosa Des Expressionismus" Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "Responsibilities of the Spirit" Mss. Incomplete, Undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - "Richard Beer - Hofmann, Diverse Vortrage" - Mss. Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Scienta Nuova - "Erste Uberle - Gungen" - Photocopy, Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - "Short Story" - Mss., Undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - "Social and Intellectual Evolution of Germany" - Lecture Notes, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - "Social Aspects of Great Individuals"/ "Soziologie der grossen personlichkeit" - Lecture outline, Undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - "Staat (Deitsche Werdensgeschichte)" - Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Strindberg Festschrift Introduction - Mss., 1947 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - "Das Symbol" - Mss., Offprints, Undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Theory of History - Mss., Undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - "Thomas Mann's 'Doktor Faustus'" Proofs, 1948 April (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Der Tod Georgs (Richard Beer - Hofmann). Introduction - Mss., Undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - "Tote Zelt. Eine Studie" - Mss., 1907 September (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - The Tower and the Abyss - Chap. 2: " Die Spaltung von Aussen" - Mss., Undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - The Tower and the Abyss - Chap. 3: "Totalosierung und Terror" Mss., Undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - The Tower and the Abyss - "Postscript - Mss., Undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - "The Transformation of Modern Fiction" - Mss., Offprint, 1955 March-1955 June (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - "Transformation of the Novel" - Mss., Notes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - "Transformation of the Novel" - Lecture text, Undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - "Transformation of the Novel" - Materials, Undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - "Die Transzendenz der Kunst" - Mss., Undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - "Umriss Einer Neuen Unviersal - Theorie" - Mss., 1933 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - "Unconscious" - Lecture Mss., Undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - "Uniqueness of German History" - Lecture Notes used as Basis for The Germans - Originals, Undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - "Uniqueness of German History" - Lecture notes used as Basis for The Germans - Photocopy, Undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - "Uniqueness of German History" - Miscellaneous Materials, Undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - "Untergang und Ubergang des epischen Kunst forms" - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - "Untergang und Ubergang des epischen Kunstforms" - Mss., Undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - "Untergang und Ubergang des epischen Kunstforms" - Typescript, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Ursprung und Wandlung des Judenhasses" - Mss., Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Urteil ohne Richter" - Mss., Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Die Verantwortung des Deutschen Volkes" - Mss., Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Die Verinnerung des Erzahlens Erster Teil" - Mss., Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Die Verinnerung des Erzahlens: Zweiter Teil" - Mss., Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Verschiedene Entwurfe" - Miscellaneous Ms., Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "W.d. mod. Romans" - Mss., Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "Das Wahre, das Gute und das Schone" - Mss., 1961 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "Das Wahre, das Gute und Das Schone" - Notes, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "Warnung an Amerika" - Mss., 1939 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "What are the Jews?" -Mss., Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "What are the Jews?" - Notebook, Undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - "What are the Jews?" - Mss. - Photocopy, Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - "What are the Jews?" - Mss., Undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - "What are the Jews?" - Tables, Charts, Undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - "Why Socialism? Which Socialism?" - Lecture Mss., 1959 November 13 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Zeit [in der Literatur]" - Mss., 1958-1961 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - "Die Zukunft des Romans" - Mss., Undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Library slips, etc., Undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Notes Slips, Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - "Johann Gottlieb Fichte's Sammtliche Werke" - Review, Undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Graeber: Jews in a Gentle World - Review, Undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Nellsonm William Allen. We Escaped, Twelve Personal Narrations of the Flight to America - Review, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Schoeps: Judisch-Christliches Religionsgesprach in Neunzehn Jahrhunderten - Review, Undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Printed Materials about Kahler/Biographical, 1913-1971; 4
  - Offprints and Clippings, 1913-1965; Undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - 60th Birthday - Clipping, Undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - 75th Birthday - Clipping, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - 80th Birthday - Clipping, 1955-1958; 1965; Undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Obituaries, Memorial Addresses, 1970-1971; Undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings about Kahler, 1930-1970; Undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Reviews of Kahler's Works, 1936-1977; 5
  - "Die Auflosung der Form", 1973 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Der deutsche Charakter in der Geschichte Europas, Undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - "Form und Entformung", 1964; Undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - The Germans, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - The Inward Turn of the Narrative, 1973-1974; Undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Israel unter den Volkern/Jews Among the Nations, 1936; 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Man the Measure, 1943-1947; 1957; 1967; Undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - The Meaning of History, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - The Orbit of Thomas Mann, 1956; 1969; Undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Out of the Labyrinth, 1967; 1969 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Der Sinn der Geschichte, 1964-1965; 1967; Undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Stefan George, 1963-1966; Undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - The Tower and the Abyss - English Reviews, Undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - The Tower and the Abyss - Italian Reviews, 1953-1964; Undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - An Exceptional Friendship (Secondary Work), 1974; 1977 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Manuscripts by Others, 1938-1964; 6
  - Anon. "Harvesting as the Basic Econmic form of Totemism" - Mss., Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bab, Julius. "Gedanken uber Preussen (Mai 1945)" - Mss, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bell, Charles G. "Newton's Triangle of Cause" - Mss., Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Bell, Charles G. "The Smiling One" - Mimeo, Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Bennett, John W. and Kurt H. Wolff. "Toward Communication Between Sociology and Anthropology, Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Borgese, G.A. "Manifesto", "First Memorandum", "Freedom and Discipline in a Vital Democracy", Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Broch, Hermann. Recommendation for Erich Kahler for a Guggenheim Fellowship, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Broch, Hermann. "Broch Uber Erich Kahler" - Photocopy, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Broch, Hermann. "Geschichte alsmoralische Anthropologie (Erich Kahlers scienza nuova)" - Mss., Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Engel, Eva. "Lavater, Mendelssohn, Lichtenberg" - Photocopy, Undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Eulenberg, Adelheid. Mss., Undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "Ein Besuch von? Mars" - Drama, Undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - "Zelfe v.d. Steinen", Undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Falk, Richard A. "On Minimizing the use of Nuclear Weapon" - Mss., Undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Ginsberg, Ernst. "Abschied" - Mss., Undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Hamburger, Michael. "Treblinka" - Mss., Undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Hiller, Robert L. "Seven Poems by Robert L. Hiller" - Mss., Undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Kiel, Anni - "Dem Andenken Erich Kahlers, 1885-1970", Undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Mann, Golo. "Fuer Erich Kahler. Am Beginn seines Einundsiebzigsten Jahres", Undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Osterle, Heinz. "Die Deutschen im Spiegel des Sozialkritschen Romans der Emigranten", 1964 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Osterle, Heinz. "The Other Germany", Undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Pannwitz, Rudolf. "Die Ruckkehr des Profeten", "Elegien und Hymnen" "Am 28. Marz 1938", 1938 March 28 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Pearce, Roy Harvey The Continuity of American Poetry - Synopsis, Undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Pearce, Roy Harvey "Historicism Come Again, To the Memory of F. Michael Krouse (1916-1955)", Undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Sahl, Hans "Fur Erich Kahler", Undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Schnitzler, Olga "Richard Beer - Hofmann" - Mss., Undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Sterba, Richard "Is Freudianism an adequate Solution for our Individual and Collective ills?", 1961 March 15 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Urzidil, Johannes, Radio Program on Kahler, Undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Zuckerkandl, Victor "Music and the Modern Mind" - Outline, Undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Zuckerkandl, Victor "Zum 70 Geburstag Erich Kahlers", 1955 October (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Offprint Collection, 1934-1971; 7
  - A, 1946; 1957; 1969 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - B, 1942-1967; Undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Boulding, Kenneth, 1960; 1964-1965; Undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - C, 1945; 1957; 1964-1965; Undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - D, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Dehn, Max, 1936-1937; 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - E, 1959; 1963 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - F, 1941-1971 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Fischer, Ruth, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Fried, Hans Ernst, 1943; 1953; Undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Fromm, Hans, 1965; 1968 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - G, 1947-1968; Undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - H, 1954; 1957; 1962; 1964 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Hempel, Carl Gustav, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Hewett - Thayer, Harvey W., 1943; 1960 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - I, J, 1967; Undated (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - K, 1946; 1966-1967; 1969; Undated (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Kann, Robert A., 1956; 1958; 1961-1962; 1967; Undated (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Kiel, Anna, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - L, 1949; 1966; 1969; Undated (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Lehnert, Herbert, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Loewenthal, Rudolf, 1947; 1958; 1960; Undated (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Lowinsky, Edward E., 1943; 1953 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Lowith, Karl, 1962; 1968 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - M, 1946-1967; Undated (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Machlup, Fritz, 1967; 1969 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Margemau, Henry, Undated (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Monas, Sidney, 1967; 1969 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - N, 1944; 1955-1956; Undated (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Maurice, 1955; 1959-1960; Undated (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Oppenheim, Felix, 1950; Undated (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Oppenheim, Paul, 1948; 1955; 1957-1958; 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - P, 1956; 1958; 1962; 1966 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Pearce, Roy Harvey, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Perl, Walter H., 1962 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - R, 1948-1949; 1964; 1967; Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Rizzardi, Alfredo, 1957; Undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Rukser, Udo, 1958-1959; 1965; 1967 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - S, 1949-1964; Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Seidlin, Oskar, 1953; 1960; Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Seifereth, Wolfgangs, 1952; 1961; Undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Slochower, Harry, 1940; 1948; 1950; Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Spitz, David, 1954; 1959 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Staraste, Wolfgang, 1960; Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Sterba, Richard F., 1967 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - T, 1946; 1952 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Tagliacozzo, Glorgio, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Trahan, ELizabeth, 1963; 1966; Undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - U, 1958; 1960 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - V, 1958; 1968 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Vordtriede, Werner, 1963; Undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - W, 1934-1968; Undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Wallach, Luitpold, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Weigand, Hermann, 1942; 1964-1965; Undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Wolfe, George V., 1948; 1966 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Wolff, Kurt H., 1967; Undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Zborowski, Mark, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Ziolkowski, Theodore, 1956; 1963-1964; 1966; Undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Zuckerkandl, Victor. Offprints, 1944; 1958; 1965 (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Materials, Collections, and Miscellany, 1910-1969; 8
  - American Association for a Democratic Germany - Materials, 1946-1947; Undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born - Materials, 1953-1954; Undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Autographen - Sammlung - Catalog, 1933; Undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - "Disintegration of Form in the Arts" - Materials, 1964; 1966-1967; Undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - "Diverse Autoren: Manuscripts, Reprints, Etc.", 1946; Undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee - Materials, 1952-1954; Undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Europa Verlag - Receipts, 1937-1938; Undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Hebrew University - Materials, 1941; 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Judaica/Hebraica - Clippings, 1919-1937; Undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Judaica/Hebraica - Clippings, Undated (Flat-file 1)
  - Judaica/Hebraica - Catalogs, 1910-1930; Undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - "Juden" - Notes, Clippings, 1930; 1935; 1940; Undated (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Mass und Wert - Materials, 1937-1938; Undated (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - McCarren Act - Materials, 1952-1954; Undated (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Ohio State University - Miscellaneous Materials, 1955; 1957; Undated (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - "Resist" - Materials, 1967-1968; Undated (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - "Unity of the Sciences" - Materials, 1953-1954; Undated (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Bohm, David "The Pleasure Principle" - Mss., Undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Bohm, David "The Role of Basic Concepts of Science in Determining the Structure of Human Relationship", Undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Candidates, 1966; Undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Documents, 1966; Undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Kahler Mss., 1953; 1961; 1966; Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Lwoff, Andre. "Molecular Societies", Undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Margenau, Henry. "The Philosophical Legacy of Quantum Theory", 1959; Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Marois Maurice. "A Biologist in the City", Undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Mather, Kirtley F. "The Unifying Organic Principle", 1965 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Miscellany, 1958; 1961; 1963; 1966; Undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Morrison, P. "The Hand of Man", Undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Offprints, 1958-1960; 1962; 1964-1966; Undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Organization, 1963; 1965-1967; Undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Piel, Gerard. "For the Living Generation", 1964 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Weiss, Paul. "Growth of Science: Its Liberating Force and Limitations", 1965 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Weiss, Paul. "A Program for a Program", Undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Van Leer Foundation - Young, Arthur Middleton "Brave New Man", Undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Vietnam - Clippings, 1965; 1967 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1937-1969; Undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Kahler Archive Lists, Undated (Box 10, Folder 22)